[Music]
so
hello good evening good day everybody
welcome to episode 135 of the ask a
bigger show
i hope you're all doing very well and
thank you for being on the show
so uh before we get into the questions
let's see who all is there with us and i
can see kushagra nikhil singh
india unleashed
vladimir putin tanishq vladimir
tanish 2k world bhumica grave walker
pink line cabs
sachin durga kishore vishal rai a bunch
of random atoms mr giga chad of india
twilight learning milestone ap singh
rathor dr abc
anand goel
rita
own
and a whole lot of other people good
evening good day to all of you some more
footy nitin
98 years
vihari sriram and lots of other people
great to have you all
tonight with me on this latest episode
of the askgaryvee show
so
today we will deal with geopolitics in
history and current affairs so
let's see what questions await us
as always you all have asked lots of
questions and okay let me take this
question first just to
uh just for the benefit of the newer
audience
so this is by v noop uh you have a very
good italian accent i live in the
caribbean i'm indian by birth and so on
like i'm at work and i cannot join live
uh how can i ask my question i did ask a
few questions with the hashtag ask
abjidjit but i did not hear from you
what's the right way to get my question
to you okay i think many people may have
this question how do you ask questions
go to any video on my channel or go to
the community page
and there are lots of community posts
there ask your question over there and
use the hashtag this hashtag do you see
this hashtag ask a widget uh let me put
that
over here can you see this hashtag here
this one here
this one
that's the hashtag you have to use it's
in two forms with the capitals and
without the capitals use this hashtag
not both anyone
and please use the correct spelling
with your question
the spelling used over here is slightly
incorrect ask abject and the hashtag has
to be
attached to the ask a widget not
separate with a space in between so if
you do that i'll be able to pick up your
questions i cannot read the thousands of
comments that come in every week but i
try to read all the query all the
comments that have this hashtag
uh incorporated in them you know that
you will hopefully get
i'll hopefully see that and i'll be able
to possibly answer your question now
yeah lots of people ask questions and
their questions are not picked up i
apologize for that there are thousands
of questions that come in every week
some people email me saying i'm i'm very
um
i'm i'm very upset with you and i'm very
disappointed with you you did not pick
my question please understand thousands
of people are questioning asking
questions every week i can only pick a
few
you want to me to pick your question ask
the best possible question you have you
asked me the same question i've answered
lots of times before i will not pick it
up most likely i have more than a
thousand videos on my channel
do a search on my channel for the
question that you haven't most likely it
may already be answered so if you do
that you'll be able to ask me questions
all right let's now get into the real
questions
okay yes uh this is something we spoke
about earlier but yeah it's it's worth
uh
taking this again
raghav says why did the us help pakistan
in maintenance of f-16 aircraft fighted
fighter jets and announced a packet
package of 450 million dollars on the
other hand sharif met putin at the seo
summit this week
and asked for cheap gas pipeline
directly into pakistan
aryan says u.s is providing upgradation
of the f-16 fleet at the same time it
also wants to sell india apaches fa-18
fighter jets reaper drones their defense
minister
yeah told our defend minister they'll
provide new technologies to india
against china
why are they playing both the sides
and shivam says u.s signed a contract
with f16 and all that
to make them capable to jam enemy
aircraft with new generation software
is this not hypocrisy of the india or
are they playing the pakistan card with
india
yeah okay good good questions
first of all the americans always accuse
indian uh commentators journalists
diplomats etc
in government
of having a cold war mentality
this pakistan card they have played is
nothing but uh straight out of the cold
war playbook
they used to arm pakistan finance
pakistan fund pakistan in the 1980s
1990s etc during the cold war 1760s also
right the americans did that constantly
for decades
and they financed pakistani terrorism in
india americans did that so this action
of theirs of offering this 450 million
dollar
upgrade package to the pakistanis for
their f-165 depends it's straight after
out of the cold war playbook yeah so
first of all the the uh when they accuse
indians of uh having a cold war
mentality they are actually playing from
the cold war playbook that's what
they're doing so uh that's point number
one now what else is there
uh they want to sell india
various uh
weapons systems apache aircraft fa 18
fighter planes yes and so on so forth uh
they want to help india against china
yeah so on the other hand they are
helping pakistan so are they not playing
both the sides of course they are
playing both the sides the americans do
not want india to rise too much
they want india to be at the same level
of strength and power and ability as it
is today
india's economy is about 3.6 billion
dollars something like that that's the
gdp yeah 3.6 trillion sorry trillion so
that's the kind of gdp strength that
india has today 3.53 trillion dollars
in the u.s doesn't want india to rise
much beyond this they want india to
remain a middle power not a very strong
power and they want to utilize this
whatever capability india has today has
a counterweight against china in order
to prevent china's rise further
but they don't want india to become the
next china
that's the worst case scenario for them
so they will
help pakistan in order to counter
balance india and they will offer india
weapons packages and so on so forth
various kinds of things in order to
counterbalance china so india is a
counter balance to china and pakistan is
a counterbalance to india that's the
game they are playing
yeah so is this hypocrisy no this is
real politics that's what they always do
they have no friends they don't believe
in having any friends even when it comes
to their relations with the uk with new
zealand with australia with canada they
treat these nations the g5 nations
uh
the five i not g5s the five eyes
alliance they treat all the other
english-speaking nations as wasall
states
and
who are expected to tow the line and do
what they are told
and uh
so that's the deal with them they they
don't believe in having any friendship
with anybody they simply want to be the
number one top dog in the world and they
will do anything
to uh
to maintain
this position that they have so they are
using pakistan to offset india to
counter balance india and to make sure
that india doesn't feel too comfortable
and
some of them say
some
western diplomats some western
journalists say that this is nothing but
the routine aid package it is not aimed
against india it is for like somebody
said here it's it's uh to help pakistan
in its anti-terrorism measures have the
pakistanis ever use the f-16s and their
fighter planes to
fight terrorists
no
everybody knows what the f-16s are
intended for they use their internet to
be used against india everyone knows the
americans also know that right and
this obviously is in response to india's
multi-alignment to india's uh
multi-alignment diplomacy multi-polar
world
diplomacy india is aligning with all
like-minded nations
yeah india is not going straight into
the u.s camp and doing whatever they are
telling us to do india is aligning
itself with france india is aligning
itself with japan in whatever way india
is aligning itself is india is
cooperating fully with russia when it
comes to the development of india with
buying oil all those things
the americans are deeply
dissatisfied with that they want india
to do exactly what we tell what they
tell india to do and india should cut
off all relations with russia and so on
that's what they want and india is also
participating in the vostok uh is going
to participate in the verstok uh
military exercises with russia
in the far east so in response
to india
not doing what the americans telling
them to do they are doing these things
now look at this look at it this way
when india cooperates with russia in a
variety of means it is
for the sake of strengthening india's
national self-defense capabilities right
it is not whatever cooperation india is
doing with russia it does not harm u.s
national security in any way whatsoever
it is simply to enhance india's national
security vis-a-vis china and pakistan
yes
whatever india is doing with russia and
other nations it's only for self-defense
purposes it's for strengthening india's
national self-defense capabilities it
does not harm
u.s national interests in any way
whatsoever
it doesn't pose any threat to american
defense
but when the americans aid pakistan it
directly
threatens india's
national interest in national defense
capabilities right they are
strengthening india's number two enemy
in a way that will make it
easier
for pakistan to hurt india if there is a
war so the americans are directly aiding
india's number two enemy against india
india is doing nothing
to aid any
of america's enemies in any way that
infringes upon the us national interest
right
so that is the kind of asymmetry that we
are seeing now right now the americans
are pretty perfectly happy to see india
bleed again in the future and they are
ensuring that pakistan will be in a
position to do that in the future that's
what the americans are ensuring are
ensuring this is a hostile act against
india
this is in this is essentially enemy
action against india so please
understand where the u.s stands
vis-a-vis india it's no friend of india
it's no friend of anybody i we can
understand why they're doing it
but
understanding doesn't mean that it's
right and understanding
why they're doing it doesn't mean that
it is good for us
right
so uh that is the deal so they also want
to sell india apache uh
attack helicopters fa-18 fighter planes
reapered drones whatever else but they
will extract a big price for that
obviously it will not be cheap it will
cost a lot of money whatever aid you
know they call everything aid we are
aiding taiwan no you're not aiding
taiwan you're selling stuff to taiwan
and taiwan is giving you money in
exchange for that it's not aid
so they they construe everything as aid
it's not aid they are selling stuff
every time there's a war it benefits the
us
financially and commercially it benefits
the various uh the northrop grumman and
lockheed martin and whatever other
defense companies they have raytheon
uh general atomics all these american
defense companies which are weapons
manufacturers it helps them immensely it
benefits them immensely it uh so so
that's why wars are profitable for the
us that's what they discovered during
world war two we made a lot of money out
of it so let's keep wars going
uh so that's what they are doing
uh the amer american action in aiding
pakistan is enemy action against india
it's a hostile act against india
and they are trying to say that you know
it's it's just a routine thing which is
not which it is not
they are greatly miffed by what india is
doing india is
not aligning itself with the u.s
completely in india is refusing to be
told what india should do
india is pursuing and com a completely
independent foreign policy which the
american say they hate the same thing
about france as well yes
uh so yeah that's that's what's
happening india is also not cooperating
with the us when it comes to the
indo-pacific
economic whatever it is uh that that new
uh organizing the organization they've
created india has pulled out of pulled
out of the trade
pillar of the new organization and so on
so yes there is significant friction
between india and the united states and
the latest action of the us is nothing
short of being enemy action against
india when i
strengthen
your enemy
and i i upgrade your enemies weapons i
am essentially saying that i am also
your enemy right that's how it works so
that's what the americans have done
so we are witnessing a deterioration of
india u.s relations for sure
and i i i believe i read this that the
indian defense minister mr rajnath singh
did speak for this american counterpart
and made it very clear that what you're
doing is is
is something that we
are greatly displeased with this is
nothing i mean i'm not i don't know what
exact words we used but yes the
displeasure has been conveyed very
clearly and very strongly to the
americans
and obviously this is going to impact
future india u.s relations
they want us to buy more weapons from
them it's going to be hard for them to
convince us to do that the fa18 i think
they should forget about it yeah
so uh we will
be open to cooperation with the us only
when it concerns and and it is concerned
with our national security and national
in our self-interest
you're gonna help us we're going to take
your help but don't expect any freebies
and don't expect any warmth in the
relationship that's the that's the thing
it's going to go so it's going to be a
transactional relationship
the previous u.s president was a
transactional president mr trump
everything was transactional so india
also i expect will go in the same
direction of the us
and we will cooperate fully when it
comes to economic
uh cooperation but when it comes to
national security cooperation and
strategic cooperation it's going to be
issue based cooperation we will examine
each issue on its merits from our
perspective and if it benefits us
then we will go ahead with that
otherwise we will reject it and that's
what india is doing that's what i call
the jaishankar doctrine i have a video
on that and i've laid out all the points
in that so what we are seeing is that
the jaishankar doctrine
in
in action right
uh so i think that's about the questions
and when it comes to sharif meeting
putin and asking for gas you know
the fact that america the us is selling
this weapons upgrade package the f-16
upgrade package to pakistan doesn't mean
that the relations are now good between
the u.s and pakistan the americans
no longer have much use for pakistan
pakistan was valuable to for them when
they were occupying afghanistan they had
invaded and occupied afghanistan they
had placed a puppet regime in place
puppet government first it was karzai
and then it was ashraf ghani these were
puppet leaders of afghanistan put in
place by the us
and they were conducting various
operations in afghanistan military
operations and so on they needed
pakistan as a staging base for that
and they needed they needed access to
the indian ocean why pakistan that's why
pakistan was valuable to them now that
they have withdrawn from pakistan and
they no longer have much more presence
in central asia pakistan is worthless to
them yeah but
they have reopened the pakistan playbook
in order to needle india and in order to
threaten india
and that's what the they've done so the
pakistanis know that no that america has
not suddenly or not become a friend
again
their big daddy is still china
yeah and
russia unfortunately needs china for now
russia still needs chinese assistance
the chinese also need russia in order to
play their games their geopolitical
games and to further their geopolitical
interests visa with the us their
ambitions of becoming the number one
superpower in the world so for that they
also temporarily need russia so russia
and china temporarily need each other
long term if you look at it long term
they are going to be adversaries and
enemies but right now they're
cooperating
so that's how the pakistan china russia
thing is working mr putin is also
playing the game yes so yeah he had a
meeting with whoever the
latest pakistani prime minister is and
i'm sure sharif right the younger
brother shari brother so yeah he must
have uh asked mr putin for whatever aid
he wants with some maybe some loans
maybe some oil gas whatever cheap yes
jeep is the word
so yeah that's going on so this the
pakistanis know that their big daddy is
china and and to some extent russia
because of the associated with china the
us is not
uh
pakistan's big daddy anymore this is
just a one-off action and maybe it will
be continued maybe the sort of aid
packages that the americans have given
once to pakistan it may happen again if
india refuses to
keeps refusing to play by america's
playbook and which is going to happen so
let's see it's interesting times ahead
you know interesting times ahead the
americans are again opening the cold war
playbook they're again bringing in the
pakistan factor uh as a stick to beat
india with let's see how far they can
carry this i am sure i can assure you
there will be consequences to this the
americans will not be able to get their
way with india and make india do what
they want so we are now witnessing a
multi-pronged tussle
the americans need india against china
but they are deeply unhappy with india's
independent foreign policy they are
trying to arm twist india into coming on
their side india is going to refuse that
india is not going to become a u.s basal
state by any means whatsoever
and there's the pakistan angle the china
angle the russia angle it's
it's complicated right we are entering a
complicated
uh
period of time in world geopolitics when
everything is in flux so that is the
situation currently
and we will keep an eye on this on this
program
okay utkarsh says
why did malaysia deny buying indian
h-a-l-t-just fighter planes and went for
the korean kai t-50 golden eagle do you
think the u.s had a hand behind this
deal because the t-50 jets are a joint
venture
between korean aerospace and lockheed
martin the american company
good question
so uh i'm not sure if it's been
officially announced or not that the
koreans have gone for i mean the the
malaysians have gone for the korean jet
but it is possible that they will go for
the korean jet so there were a number of
planes in the fray number of fighter
planes that they were considering uh
there's a turkish lightweight fighter
plane i forget the name
horjet i think it's called the horjet
h-u-r-j-t herjet it's a turkish fighter
plane that is still currently under
development that was in the frame the
china pakistani the chinese pakistani
jf-17 thing was also in the fray
uh what else was there
i think the mig 35 one of the mig mig
fighter planes either 29 or 35 most
likely 35 was also in the fray they just
was there and the korean golden eagle
was also in the fray and
the the top three that they had selected
was where the turkish fighter plane i
think and the korean plane and the
indian plane and the top two were the
korean plane in the indian plane and now
anytime i suppose they will make a
decision or i'm not sure if it's been
announced thus far but it looks like i
mean that's what the media is
speculating that maybe they will go for
the
golden eagle the korean fighter plane
which is a light fighter plane which is
a derivative an advanced derivative of
the f-16 fight fighting falcon the 1970s
american plane which they are also
trying to offer to india
yeah so uh it's possible that the
malaysians will go for the korean plane
the thing is the korean plane is much
cheaper than the indian fighter plane
out of all these aircraft the indian
fighter plane the pages was the most
expensive i think the unit price was
about 35 40 approximately 40 million
dollars per piece which is quite
expensive for the size
it's because the the indian fighter
plane has the most capability the most
advanced capabilities and the best
weapon systems and all that and the
india was offering much more they were
india was offering the malaysians uh
access i mean some kind of upgrades to
their sukhoi fighter planes as well they
also have a variant of the sukhoi mk30
fighter plane
so india was offering assistance in
spares and maintenance of that as well
there was a package real india was
offering but maybe they would go for the
korean gold golden eagle it's a
possibility maybe even a likelihood i'm
not sure if it's in announce so
if this indeed happens
that the malaysians go for the korean
jet
which is not as capable as a tejas
then is the u.s behind that well like
you mentioned utkars you are right that
the
american company lockheed martin is
indeed
a
one of the one of the companies that was
involved in the development
of this t-50 fighter jet along with
korean the the korean company i think
lockheed martin has a 13 or 15 percent
stake in the development and i think i
believe the radar and
the radar is developed by lockheed
martin some other avionics and some
other components may be also developed
by lockheed martin uh i also i think
it's also got a general electric uh jet
engine yes
so many of the components come from the
us and yes
and as we know and and unless you don't
well we should know this south korea is
a u.s warsaw state south korea
has been under permanent u.s occupation
since the 1950s since the end of the
korean war since since the korean war
started essentially right the u.s has
had a permanent presence in
south korea since that time
so uh
it's it's therefore not surprising if
the u.s had some say in this yeah
so uh of course nothing has officially
been announced that the americans aren't
present the
the malaysians into this or whatever but
yes if the malaysians buy the korean
fighter plane then the u.s will benefit
lockheed martin will benefit and overall
india will
it will
india will not benefit right
if they acquire 20 or 30
pages fighter planes it's going to be
good for the indian economy for the
indian
uh
defense manufacturing ecosystem and all
that so maybe they don't want this to
happen
and they want the benefit instead to go
to korea
and the u.s so it is certainly a
possibility if they are behind this they
will certainly not announce that
these things are always kept under wraps
and the game is played in the shadows
right the game of influence the game of
geopolitics so it is certainly a
possibility if the malaysians go with
the k a i
t 50 golden eagle then it is i would say
quite likely
that
at least a certain amount percentage of
the decision
was influenced by the u.s and you know
here's the thing
this golden eagle it's been flying i
think since 2012 or something about a
decade and from 2012 i'm not sure maybe
before 2012 i'm not really sure but from
2012 until 2022 this year there have
been six crashes
of this aircraft right so it's not got a
very good record it's got a patchy
record
six crashes in ten years is not a small
amount i think the total number that has
been built thus far is about 200 out of
which six have crashed about three
percent crash rate which is not a very
encouraging sign
yeah so that's also there in the
malaysians if they go for it they they
know that they are purchasing an
aircraft that has this sort of track
record
so uh yeah let's see how it goes it is
possible they may go for this aircraft
and in that case definitely there would
be an american hand to some extent
behind this
gopi says why did modi ji
say that today is not an era
of war to president putin
so uh yeah let me put something on the
screen what has the media being saying
being saying about this what is the
media been saying about this
so yeah
this week
you had the
shanghai cooperation uh organization
seos summit in samarkand
uzbekistan
and uh mr modi did meet mr putin
a bilateral meeting on the sidelines of
the of the summit
so here's what sri ian bremerjee has to
say mr ian bremer is
a political scientist
yeah he's a political scientist and he's
got a big following on twitter so he
says
that modi putting putin on notice india
wants the ukraine war to end
a disastrous shanghai cooperation summit
for the russian dictator oh my goodness
what a disaster according to sri ian
bremerjee what else
here's what reuters has to say
reuters what's oh yes india's modi
assails putin
over the ukraine war mamma mia what a
terrible terrible
thing to happen
do they look like they does mr modi look
like he is about to assail mr putin
anyhow that's what uh the media is
saying i'm
when i say media i mean the western
media
so what really happened is the question
right this is what the media has been
saying i've just given you a sample of
that a taste of that a flavor of that of
what the western media said maybe the
indian media may also be towing this
line if you look at various big india
media organizations they essentially to
the western line whether it is on tv
whether it's on
on the internet whether it is in print
or whatever they typically told the
western line your favorite news reader
whoever he or she is typically chose the
question line so what happened
so we had this bilateral meeting between
mr modi mr putin
on the sidelines of the seo summit and
mr modi did say
that during this meeting
that the modern era is not the era of
war
he said that
what does it mean it's a general
statement
it does not target or or it is not
pointed at any individual or any nation
he said he made the general statement
that the modern era is not the ira war
and he exchanged the customary
diplomatic greetings with shri putinji
and there was a general statement in
general statements for dialogue for
diplomacy including this this statement
that the modern era is not the ira for
war right
mr modi did not specify
the ukraine conflict he just said the
iraq war and he also did not
even if with with the reference to the
ukraine conflict he did not specify who
instigated the conflict and prompted the
war
the entire universe
known universe
and all the sentient beings in the known
universe know
that there was a maidan coup it was a
color revolution instituted by the
united states the u.s has perfected the
art of instigating these colon
revolutions again and again and again
iteratively so the maidan revolution was
an undemocratic coup against the
constitutionally elected government it
was an unconstitutional undemocratic
coup orchestrated by the us we know that
so you had the maidan coup then you also
have the
long term steady expansion of nato
eastwards in contravention of every
single agreement and all
of the agreement they had with the earth
while ussr in the and with russia
and we also have the ongoing long-term
decade plus long western training in
support
of
ukrainian politicians and later on after
the medan coup of the ukrainian
neo-nazis yes all these things triggered
the ukraine
conflict so mr mo they did not mention
who instigated the conflict and prompted
the war and he certainly did not play
point any fingers at either mr putin
or
at russia
right so he just made some general
statements for the sake of diplomacy
these are the typical diplomatic
statements that you have in the
uh that you have when two leaders meet
in front of the cameras and then there
was a closed door meeting with where
there were no journalists
and no cameras
and after the closed-door meeting mr
modi spoke about the unbreakable
friendship between india and russia
and he also said that mr modi that mr
modi and mr putin put in their closed
door meeting was wonderful
so
where does mr modi assail
mr putin in any of this take a look
again what is this nonsense wisdom that
india's modi assails putin there was no
no assault nothing of the sort
this is a complete fabrication they are
twisting facts to suit their narratives
and agendas and once again if it ever
loads shri ian bremerjee what he said
yeah this here modi putting putin on
notice what nonsense he's making things
up to suit his agenda
so that's what you typically see these
days you see
it's all about
furthering your agenda the truth is not
important there is no such thing as
truth in journalism that's why people
call this the post-truth era the truth
no longer matters it's only propaganda
and perceptions that matter
and you can create an avalanche of
propaganda and people will start
believing anything so that is where we
are today all right so there was no such
thing uh mr modi just made a simple
status standard diplomatic statement
that the current era the modern era is
not the era for war which which is just
a general statement and he is not laying
the blame on mr putin or on russia
kalyan says
india is going to take the leadership of
the seo in the upcoming 12 months and
the seo summit is already started today
i mean this must be like a couple of
days ago
and pm modi g is going on friday will
the president of china interact with
modi g after galwan summit galwan valley
incident
or vice versa with modi j
so the the summit is already over
uh it was thursday friday today is
sunday
i believe mr modi must be back home now
back back in india
so what happened during the summit mr
modi had multiple bilateral meetings
with various leaders he
met as we discussed uh shri vladimir
putinji
mr modi also met the president of turkey
shri richard
the great
great friend of mr modi he also met
uzbekistan's leader chavukat mirzoyev
and he also met iran's leader ibrahim
rajisi so he had at least four bilateral
meetings and
there was no meeting with mr xi jinping
there was no bilateral meeting with mr
xi jinping as far as i know there was no
handshake between mr modi and mr xi
jinping there was no hello there was no
smile nothing they did stand next to
each other in the group photograph
once and they stood apart also in a
different group photograph so it's clear
that there were no
pleasantries
no greetings
no handshakes no smiles nothing
between the leaders of india and china
nothing at all
you can see the tensions are very clear
very apparent
the vibe the vibe is very cold yes i
mean mr modi even met mr abdulgan with
india and turkey don't have the warmest
of relationships at the best of times
and yet mr modi had a very
you know pleasant and warm meeting with
mr erdogan but no such thing was there
with with mr xi jinping so yes we are
currently going through a period of
turmoil in india china relations
the relations are very tense they are
quite hostile the two leaders did not
even
smile at each other they did not even
say a single simple hello
so yes that is the situation that tells
you everything you need to know and of
course mr modi did not meet with the
pakistani the latest
temporary prime minister whoever it is
uh and there was no need for that
because the pakistani prime minister
does not really have any power in
pakistan we know that right it's just uh
he's just a figurehead a puppet sock
puppet the
hand in the sock puppet behind the
soccer ball is that of the army
so yes that is the situation no
talks between mr modi and mr xi jinping
no agreement no nothing
the relationship is just as cold
and uh
hostile
as it has been
so this was the first time they met in
two three years i would say and it was
hardly a meeting at all they just stood
next to each other did not look at each
other no eye contact nothing so yes that
tells you everything you need to know
about the relations currently between
india and china
harsh says your view on the chinese
response to the sco summit
xi jinping china's leader said that he
will support india's presidency
it's just another standard diplomatic
statement see the shanghai cooperation
organization the seo it has a rotating
presidency
yeah the presidency rotates every year
there are how many like six seven
whatever members six one eight
the membership increases from time to
time five six seven i think there are
eight members right now if i'm not
mistaken maybe more maybe less i think
eight or nine eight i think
so these eight and there are a bunch of
observer uh certain countries have
observer status and so on so forth
there's typically a number of people
there but the core group is is about
eight people the first five plus india
and pakistan plus iran which was
inducted this year so that should be
eight yeah you can look it up if you
want to
so there is a rotating presidency every
year a new nation becomes president for
one year
so at the end of the summer
summit which happened this week india
became the president india assumed the
presidency of the grouping and this will
last for one year until
late 2023 maybe
we have september right now
most likely until september 2023 and as
a consequence of this next year there's
going to be a summit there's a summit
every year so next year's summit will be
held in india at the place of in india's
choosing maybe delhi maybe somewhere
else mr modi will and the government of
india decide so that's a simple thing
and this is something that is just a
matter of course there is nothing
special
associated with being the president it's
a ceremonial kind of thing you don't
have any special decision making powers
or any such thing it's just a routine
thing the transfer of the press of the
rotating presidency year after year from
one nation to another so right now it's
india's turn and india will host the
next summit and mr xi jinping made the
standard diplomatic statement that yes
we support india's presidency blah blah
blah that's it it means nothing it
doesn't mean any throwing of the ties in
a friendly relation between the india
china it means nothing of the thought
it's just a standard diplomatic
statement and it's a routine
occurrence in the seo
uh pranav says
if you had a chance to advise modi g or
mr s
regarding their foreign policy with the
us in european countries which kind of
has gone downhill said since we did not
align ourselves with them on ukraine
versus russia matter what would my
advice be okay first of all who am i to
advise the prime minister and the
foreign minister of india they
understand diplomacy and geopolitics and
international relations far better than
me they are experienced in this they
have been doing this for a very long
time
so first of all see the thing is this
many people who
prognosticate about geopolitics who
speak about geopolitics
many of them
become too big for their books and they
start thinking they can advise everybody
there are various
news channels and youtube channels
that every day say that mr modi has got
his foreign policy wrong and dr shankar
is doing the wrong thing or somebody
else in the government is is too big for
his or her boots or whatever and they
they portray themselves as having all
the answers
and being in a position to prognosticate
and
advise the government and show what is
the right way as opposed to what the
indian government is doing right i think
that that reeks of arrogance
yes
i am very clear that i am simply an
observer
and i am i am nobody to give any advice
to the indian government especially to
people as as experienced
and as great as mr modi and dr jason and
yeah what i would say if i have to say
nothing is that they are doing exactly
the right thing
the indian foreign policy is on the
right track it is the correct foreign
policy what i have called the jaishankar
doctrine is essentially an extension of
the modi doctrine
what is being done by the indian
government is
what is needed
vis-a-vis india's national interest
long-term national interest india is
pursuing an independent foreign policy
india is not
going on its knees in front of any major
power vis whether it is china or whether
it is the us india is not allowing
itself to be armed twisted in
international relations in geopolitics
and all that and it is an admirable
foreign policy there are certain
compulsions that we have because we are
not
a superpower india is still a middle
power india still needs the cooperation
of lots of nations including the us
including china as well in some cases
for its growth for its long-term growth
india is currently walking doing a
tightrope work walk india has to anyhow
ensure that it reaches the 10 trillion
dollar mark of its economy without any
major mishaps like going to war with
somebody so india
needs to
balance its its international policy and
thus far it's doing a very good job so
all i would say is that the
foreign policy that in india is pursuing
is an excellent foreign policy it is for
the first time i'm happy to see
indian government's foreign policy and
it needs to continue continue this way
despite all the provocations and despite
all the pressure that comes in from
various sites whether it is from the
chinese side whether it's the american
side whether it's from nato from europe
or whoever else
india needs to stay the course and the
only objective is to further india's
long-term national interest that's the
deal so we are on the very much on the
right track
ritesh goel says
recently the french foreign minister
came on a three-day visit to india and
she said that she is here to offer a no
limits partnership to india she also
said that france would like to be a
defense partner rather than a defense
hardware supplier how would the u.s
react to this given that france and the
us are nato allies does it mean that
france will help india with nuclear
attack submarines is it something like
that the is it like something they that
the russians and chinese have
okay
uh yes the french foreign minister
recently came to india and she met with
mr modi most likely with mr rajnath as
well and maybe some other important
indian officials and yes she did limit
what she called she did offer what she
calls a no limits partnership to india
and france would like to be a defense
partner other than a different supplier
what does it mean it means that france
is open to transferring certain
technologies to india at the right price
see there is there are no freebies and
gifts in geopolitics every nation will
do
will will pursue its own national
interest it's it's self-interest first
now when your national interest when the
national interests of two nations align
then they can certainly cooperate in a
mutually beneficial manner so france
is always under pressure from the u.s
the french the french had a deal with
australia wherein they were supposed to
sell a number of
submarines to australia
scorpion submarines i believe a certain
variant of the scorpion submission i
think it was scorpions yes
and
the deal was signed it was finalized it
was
on its way
and then the australians pulled out of
it because they were armed twisted by
the americans and now they are going to
purchase very expensive american nuclear
submarines
and they will acquire them about 20
years or so from now it's a long term
deals over the next 15 20 years they
will have nothing
the americans arm twisted the
australians into pulling out of a deal
they had signed and finalized with
france
yeah
so obviously the french are very upset
about this
yes france is the only nation in western
europe and the only nation in the
european union and the only nation in
nato that has a quasi-independent
foreign policy
yeah they are not truly vassal state of
the us unlike all the other western
european nations
the french are not vassal states they
have a quasi-independent a reasonably
independent foreign policy they still
are indeed towing the u.s line on
ukraine and all that because they have
compulsions but as far as possible they
want to have an independent foreign
policy and they are very proud of being
separate from the anglo-sphere from the
anglo-saxon empire
and being a distinct
uh culture and civilization that's what
they are proud of i mean it's a
thousand-year-old civilization but let's
give
let's give them that
so
the french would very much like to
cooperate with india as long as it
benefits them as well
so india does
need india does want various
technologies jet engine technology is
something india very much wants asap as
soon as possible the french have that
they have this company called snikema
safar whatever
and
they have expressed a willingness to
transfer jet engine technology to india
and help the kaveri project and and make
it
you know reach its logical conclusion
but in exchange for that they will
obviously want money and not small
amounts of money so that's the deal
so they are see most nations will offer
you hardware
but they will not offer you the know-how
the technology the understanding let's
see let's say this french have built six
scorpion submarines for india the
submarines were built in india
in indian dockyards so
tomorrow india can build more of those
submarines with the same hull
characteristics and all that but certain
things will not be shared with india the
acoustic signatures and the the air
independent propulsion if there is any
and various other technologies that are
very hard to develop yeah india can make
the same hull of a submarine but inside
i mean the the various technologies that
that go inside will not be shared
so uh
so the french are willing to share some
technologies at the right price
obviously the price would be high jet
engine technology perhaps maybe
submarine technology may be something
else so what the lady is essentially
saying is that france is open to
negotiate and france will at the right
price transfer
certain technologies or maybe many
technologies but india will have to be
very careful to ensure that
for that price we get the entire
technology and technology and something
should not be left out so it's it's
something that will that
needs careful appraisal
but the good thing is that they are
willing to play ball yes
and india and france have good relations
have had good relations for a
significantly long time the french even
offered india i believe
um which aircraft what was it the mirage
the mirage 2000 they had offered to
transfer the entire mirage 2000 factory
to india and
let india build 200 or as many jets as
india wanted this is in the late 1990s
and the governments at the time were
coalition governments and
temporary governments so this deal never
happened
the entire jet engine problem the the
jet fighter problem would have been
resolved right there
yeah
so india lost a huge a golden
opportunity at that time so the french
have always been willing
to cooperate with india in a variety of
in a variety of ways when india tested
nuclear weapons in 1998 the french were
the only western nation not to condemn
india
so india and france have a good
understanding india and france have good
relations the leaders of india and
france have very good warm friendly
personal relations
this partnership this relationship can
certainly go forward but india will
obviously have to pay a hefty price for
any technology that it acquires from
france so that is where we are vis-a-vis
india and france there is a lot of
potential in this relationship
and france has
a big uh geopolitical
angle in the indian ocean region france
is a major indian ocean
power naval power in case you don't know
let me show you the map ah we haven't
had the map today so let's go to the map
where is the map
let's bring in the map here's the map
here is the map
check it out this is the
huge vast expanse of real estate
maritime real estate called the indian
ocean region it essentially
is
uh
something that india considers to be a
strategic backyard now why do i say
france is an indian ocean
maritime power
because it has something called
uh where is it
yes this island called reunion
it belongs to france france possesses
this island
mauritius used to be a french possession
port machurrah i believe belongs to
france if i'm not mistaken
and there are various uh islands south
of this territory
that could see the french southern and
antarctic lands
and so on that belong to france even the
seychelles have a history of
french involvement here are the
seychelles over here yeah all the names
in this in this uh
archipelago are french names
and so on so france still has
possessions in the indian ocean it is a
a region that is of great interest to
france and the french navy does have a
presence in various parts of the indian
ocean and as a consequence there is
cooperation between india and france in
various naval
and maritime and military matters
and that's where india and france have
common interests in keeping this region
free
of unfriendly actors which essentially
means china
to a large extent and to a lesser extent
southern certain other
nations that india and france don't have
very good relations with
we can
keep that up to your imagination
right so that's the deal between indian
friends
all right a whole lot of questions uh so
yeah i got a lot of questions for about
about this matter so i'm putting a few
of these to represent those bhumika says
india will spend seven thousand seventy
five thousand crores on the great
andaman and nicowar island the great
nicobar island
are environmentalist
concerns justified is it going to is it
not going to impact the aboriginal
tribes
why is it important for us from a
strategic point of view
the gui has approved seventy five
thousand group crore worth of projects
in the great nicobar island how does
this counter china's string of pearl
strategy and so on
webov says the same thing
environmentalists are raising concerns
that eight lake trees are going to be
cut
srijesh says
transshipment port to india
how important is it will this be a game
changer for the indian economy and so on
lots of questions about this particular
matter so let us discuss this first of
all where is it
where is the great nicobaria island
where is this island let's go to the map
once again and the great nicobar island
where is it
that's the andamans these are the
nicobars and this is the great nicobar
island this one here
so this essentially is the island that
represents the southernmost point of
india
the great nicobar island and
india has approved the government of
india has approved a
a big
massive project worth i think 9.4
billion dollars in today's money which
is 75 000 crore rupees
and it's going to be a game changer and
we uh the
indian government has already
constructed i believe a high speed fiber
optic cable between chennai i believe
and this island
this entire region uh you will have high
speed internet now onwards starting very
soon i believe
uh in the andaman nicobar islands i
think in port blair you will have a
speed of 400 gbps
in other parts of the archipelago you
will have a speed of 200 gbps which is
good and so on that's what we hear
but that is not the main thing the main
thing is the
big investment that's coming in
yeah so what is going to be built a
massive port will be built yeah
uh there will be a
township or a small city or town will be
built and obviously a power generating
station
and this will be a transshipment port
that will be able to uh handle vast
amounts vast amounts of cargo
will it have military dimension well
nothing has been announced but you can
never rule that out obviously
because this is the southernmost point
of the region it is at the very
mouth of the very strategically
important malacca strait
which is a very important choke point
which kind of constrains china
and it is one of china's achilles heels
yes because of all the uh
all the trade that
all the all the goods all the cargo that
passes
that passes out that goes out of china
or goes into china passes through the
malacca strait and the great nicobar
island sits right there at the mouth of
the strait so if india has a massive
naval capability over here whether it's
a civilian port which obviously will
have military capabilities then
obviously it's a game changer for india
so it will have trade uh it will have
trade benefits it's going to make india
a major player it's going to be one of
the india's major ports here
and of course it will have a military
dimension
any port which can handle massive ships
can handle massive warships as well yes
so yeah i'm sure it will have dual use
capabilities there are various ports in
india that have dual use capabilities
they are used in a multitude of ways so
this is going to be that
so yes of course you will have to cut
down some trees maybe eighty eight
hundred thousand trees or whatever the
number is
that is unfortunately inevitable the
long term national interest is paramount
a few trees can be
planted somewhere else again to replace
what we have cut here see if you look at
the past
seven eight years india's forest cover
is gradually increasing india is the
only major nation whose forest cover
percentage is growing year after week
after year so the government is doing
everything it can
as opposed to other major nations when
it comes to reforestation and and and
safeguarding the environment so india is
the last nation you can
accuse
of being anti-environment india is doing
more than most other major nations if
not all other major nations including
the developed world yes india's forest
cover is growing year after year so
in light of that a few trees being cut
down for the sake of india's national
security is
a sacrifice we are willing to make yes
there are indeed
an aboriginal uh people who live here
and uh they have been isolated for a
long time they are not the sentinelese
people they are i forget the name of the
of the tribe
i am sure they will be taken care of
india has been extremely
uh sensitive when it comes to matters
related to these isolated populations we
have the north central island over here
which india is
ensuring that nobody is allowed to come
here right recently some ridiculous
american preacher tried to go there with
the bible and he was shot to death with
arrows by the people of this island and
so be it
so india has ensured that this island
and the people who live here north
central island are
not interfered with in any way
whatsoever nobody is allowed to go to
the island whether it's indian citizens
or foreigners yes this essentially is an
indian protectorate a self-governing
indian protectorate india does not
implement indian law there and india
allows the people of that region of that
island to live life as they please
according to their own customs so india
has been is extremely sensitive
to the interests of these tribal
populations
when it comes to the people of great
negobar i am sure everything will be
done to ensure that their
well-being
is safeguarded more than what the more
than the well-being of other indigenous
peoples
are safeguarded in whether it's
australia or new zealand or north
america or south america india does far
better than them so these concerns are
completely misplaced i i can understand
where the concerns come from from they
come from outside india and in when from
from quarters within india that are
funded and financed by
foreign powers so that's fine yeah we we
need not concern ourselves with that
so the
forest issue will be taken care of we
will plant other trees elsewhere to
ensure that there is no uh
that to offset the trees that will be
cut here i am sure that the rest of the
great nagobah island will or the
environment environment will also be
taken care of very well and the
aboriginal people the tribe and tribal
people their
well-being will also be safeguarded but
india's national interest has to be
paramount which is why this particular
project is going to take off
and yes see the deal is this the
question was about the chinese string of
pearls strategy so china's a string of
purse strategy is about encircling india
with a network of chinese bases
there is this base in hambantota they
wanted to have a base in maldives a
naval base there is a base in djibouti
there is one in in
in guadalajara in pakistan
they want to have a port in bangladesh
maybe in burma
maybe in malaysia as well so they want
to encircle india with these the chinese
want to encircle india with this
so-called string of pearls so to counter
that india needs to build its own
maritime and naval infrastructure and
this will go a long way towards doing
that
and obviously there is going to be
something i expect there will be air
force bases also coming up in this
region because if you have a massive
port
establishment established over here you
need to safeguard it in a variety of
ways including with air power
so i expect that
whatever air force capabilities we have
in this region will be enhanced
significantly which is great
so india should build its own network of
of naval bases air force bases in this
region which will ensure that whatever
gains the chinese are making will be
offset or or neutralized or overwhelmed
so yes now finally i have been saying
this for more than a year that why is
india not doing anything to upgrade its
infrastructure in the andaman nicobar
region well here is the answer
it's happening and i'm so glad to see
this
so yes overall a very good development
from the
economic perspective from the trade
perspective from the trans shipment
perspective and also from the
geopolitical geostrategic and naval
perspective excellent development all
around it needs to continue continue
continue this is just this has to be
just the first step one the first step
of many but an excellent
strong move in the right direction
lunchimba says jordan peterson says
britain is the only country which
who helped get rid of slavery are some
of his points true
and
the other question is
jordan peterson recently said africa is
not poor because of colonization
what's your opinion
uh
there was a time when i used to actually
enjoy
you know listening to jordan peterson
once in a while he used to make sense
but off late it looks like he has been
drinking too much of his own kool-aid
which means he's become
inflated with his self sense of
self-importance because he got so much
so much praise from various quarters and
now he is all puffed up with ego and
pride and arrogance and you can see the
real daughter jordan peterson emerging
out of what we used
what we thought he used to be
so he recently had this clip on his
channel i unfortunately watched it just
to understand what was being said
so the main theme
of this he had a discussion on his
channel youtube channel he's a youtube
channel he had a discussion with an
african lady her name is uh i forget her
name uh she's somebody i'm not i mean if
you if you look for search for her on
the internet it doesn't tell you what
nation she's from it just says africa
africa africa as if africa is a nation
so i'm not sure which country within
africa she
hails from but it looks like she's based
in the us she's somebody who speaks
english well and these people are very
youthful for the west
indigenous peoples
who speak good english and who parrot
the western narrative so the theme of
this discussion the main claim was that
africans are responsible for africa's
underdevelopment it's all because of the
greed and corruption of the people who
are in power in africa and why do
africans essentially keep on electing
such people
so it's all
all of it is
because of the africans themselves they
are the ones who are responsible for
this and this lady that mr peterson dr
peterson interviewed
she was going on and on about
a claim that she was making that english
common law is a gift from the gods no
not the gods the god the only one the
one and only god the true god yeah
english common law is a gift from god
that's what she kept on saying right
now these
individuals they were totally
bypassing and neglecting
the fact that africa used to be a very
highly developed place it's a massive
continent
massive huge continent it dwarfs india
and north america and the u.s and china
and everything you can fit all of these
nations into africa and still you have a
lot of room to spare it's a massive
continent they had
empires they had kingdoms they had
civilizations there was an enormous
amount of prosperity and development and
culture in africa before the european
scheme put food there and the europeans
destroyed africa thoroughly
in the late 20th or 19th century or
early 20th century i forget when the
kingdom of benin the great city of benin
was destroyed in just one day by the
british
it was an incredibly highly developed
and advanced city and a very very
prosperous very rich kingdom it was
destroyed in just one day the whole city
was raised to the ground and today
people live there in shanty towns in
slums
if africa is poor it's because of
western colonization
uh mostly english-speaking colonization
of course the belgians were involved in
this they were also culpable the the
germans were there all the western
nations including france are responsible
for the complete destruction of not just
the african economy but the african
civilizations
yeah but these these people like jordan
peterson etc they want to essentially
they want to
employ
or use africans who speak english good
the good english and who are
who who are willing to parrot the
western narrative they want to use such
people in order to make it look like see
it's not i who i'm saying it it's
africans watching it therefore i must be
right yeah
have you heard of ccl roads cecil rhodes
was a british capitalist and politician
and imperialist and racist and mining
magnet and enslaver and destroyer of
africa who lived in the 19th century he
died in the early 20th century right he
he was a politician who essentially
became the president of prime minister
whatever of the cape colony
down south in south uh in south africa
he wanted the west he wanted england
to own africa from the cape
to cairo
from the southernmost point to the
northernmost point yeah he was financed
by rochshield and company
which is a corporation that still exists
yeah so his his mining activities and
whatever else he was doing it was all
financed by rothschild company he was
the founder of the dbr's
diamond company which still exists which
is still making enormous profits out of
diamonds diamonds are quite common
but what dbs does is that it holds all
the diamond in the world
and it sells maybe one or two percent
per year so that the prices are kept
artificially high diamonds are quite
common in the earth
well in the earth surface earth's crust
etc so this fellow cecil rhodes was the
founder of the dbs company he was the
founder of the british south africa
company which was into materials in
mining he was the founder of the
consolidated gold fields company which
existed until 1988 yeah
and he was a destroyer of africa he was
a racist he was an imperialist he
indulged in various forms of slavery the
british are the masters of slavery they
instituted the slavery so many times a
thousand years ago more than 10 percent
of the people who lived in
england were slaves that were copper or
metal collars from birth to death yeah
and the cecil rhodes is a great example
of of of these attitudes
and after he died in his will he left
behind money for the so-called cecil
rhodes scholarship the objective of the
cecil rhodes scholarship is to promote
unity among english-speaking nations is
that since it's essentially a
scholarship given to people to study at
oxford this perpetuates
the idea of british
supremacy and primacy and many indians
benefit benefit from this scholarship
many
prominent indians promote
the cecil rhodes scholarship from time
to time including people who are even
today closely associated with the
government of india i will not name
anybody look it up yourself
many indians still perpetuate still
promote
this rhodes scholarship right
so jordan peterson
has
shown his true face
he is
essentially a white supremacist
yeah his entire perspective is
occidentalist it's eurocentric he says
that western civilization is the is the
greatest thing that ever happened
in the world
everyone knows what western civilization
was built on built upon the the late
shri uh the late mr mohandas gandhi of
whom i am no big fan
he said that western civilization would
have been a good idea if it actually
existed or something to the defect yeah
western civilization is actually the
western empire it's the anglo-saxon
empire which was built upon the
slavery and destruction and genocide of
of india and africa to some extent china
and also
of north america and the spanish empire
was built upon the destruction
of south america
parts of africa as well and
philippines parts of eastern asia and
saul the entire west is built upon
slavery genocide and plunder and jordan
peterson says that western civilization
whatever it is is the greatest thing
that ever happened in human in human
history
and he keeps on perpetuating these
narratives that you know if people are
poor if people
uh
are in a bad condition and so on it's
because of their it's their own fault he
is essentially blaming the victim
so yeah it's it's uh disappointing to
see somebody of mr dr peterson's stature
doing this but he uh it's disappointing
but not surprising yeah so i used to
kind of enjoy listening to him speak a
few years ago when he used to speak
about uh
marxism and those things but yeah
nowadays i think he's shown his true
true true colors
it's uh
he is
an apologist apologist of of uh
western colonization
of slavery of imperialism of white
supremacy and everything else associated
with it so yeah that is what i have to
say about this matter
okay blob dobb
says have you seen the most famous
american conservative tucker carlson say
on its program that britain left india a
civilization and indians can't create
architecture like the old victoria
terminus in mumbai
neil says
your views on tucker carlson saying
british left india with a civilization a
language
a legal system schools churches oh thank
you sir you showed it churches which are
still in use today and british ruled
everywhere they went with unmatched
decency
and after they left africa it went to
ruins because the africans could not
manage themselves they are uncivilized
primitive people no
so why do people believe this and
justify colonial crimes like this
especially in the west
you see
beneath the veneer the thin veneer of
civilization and decency that the where
this is the true true nature this is
that
this is what they truly believe
eurocentrism
imperialism colonialism these
values are still very deeply ingrained
in the west
and with that comes racism and white
supremacy as a sense that white people
people with white skin are superior to
people with darker with darker skin
that is inherent in all these claims
whether it is jordan peterson whether it
is tucker carlson whether it's somebody
else
you you had hillary clinton speaking
about people getting off the reservation
which is a horribly offensive and racist
term against the native people of the of
of the americas yeah
racism is is inbuilt in the society it
is part of the fabric of society in the
west unfortunately i'm not saying all
western people are racist there are many
decent people in the west but
the
structure of western of of the
anglo-saxon empire is built on a
foundation of imperialism colonialism
slavery
and racism and white supremacy yes they
even used to treat the irish people as
as subhumans for the longest time
until they had to oppress the black
people the african origin americans and
the native americans it's only then that
they elevated the people of ireland or
irish origin people to the status of
full white people
yeah so yeah it's it's it's a sordid
history
and yeah you you had tucker carlson
speak about this he when it comes to
india they can still be racist because
india indians are mostly still still
hindus and hinduism is to be denigrated
so
you may not say bad things these is
about about people of african origin you
may not say bad things about people who
practice an abrahamic religion yes
because it would be a certain kind of
phobia but it's perfectly fine
to use racist terminology and racist
slurs against people of india especially
those who are christians those were not
christians especially those who are
hindus
and so that's the deal
and takar khalsa lots of indians support
the american right
which is the republican party
yes well tucker carlson is on the right
of the american political divide he's a
conservative yeah and there you have him
expressing
the same
uh
essentially the same viewpoint and it's
interesting to note that uh tulsi
gabbard is a regular
uh
is a regular participant on
tucker carlson's
broadcasts um i am not trying to throw
any shade tools she's a good lady yeah
she's one of the few american
politicians who openly condemns hindu
phobia and who is actually on india's
side as far as i can see so i'm not
trying to throw any shade at tulsi but
yeah this is the deal with tucker
carlson he is clearly a white
supremacist and a racist and he believes
that
their so-called civilization
is the only civilization that ever was
and before them india was india and
africa were primitive and barbaric and
savage lands
uh full of hiddens and now that india
has
uh british architecture and british
language and british legal system
british schools british education and
church is good god
that's why india is now civilized this
is textbook racism this is textbook
imperialism
and so on so yeah it's i'm not surprised
and it's it's just i would say
shameful that people in the west
prominent people in the west still
espouse such
opinions openly
that's the deal that that of course is
the foundation of western culture and
civilization
manmath says what is this thing going on
in the american academia
about
this term south asia instead of the
indian subcontinent
any indian achievement they name it as
south asian and any negative aspect they
will call it indian what is the reason
behind this entire south asian narrative
so lots of people have asked this
question i've just taken this one as a
representative of all those questions
you know there is no such okay let's
understand what is asia
they say that india the indian
subcontinent continent they want to call
it south asia so that the term indian is
not used
it has always been the indian
subcontinent but now the americans want
to call it south asia so that the term
indian doesn't come into the picture now
to understand the origins of all this
first of all
we have something called asia do you see
a continent called asia here
is there a separate asia in europe
no
it's just one
land mass
which some people call eurasia there is
no
geographical
boundary or separation
between
what they call europe and what they call
asia so where did this concept of asia
come from my dear friends are you aware
are you aware of where this concept this
name asia came from
let me uh
throw a little bit of light on that yeah
because this is important we need to
know this
look here
this is a map of the roman empire at its
greatest extent whatever year it is all
right
so the red shaded portion is the western
part of the peninsula of anatolia
anatolia is present in turkey i mean
more than 90 percent of turkey presented
turkey is anatolia anatolia was
historically
greek
so this red shaded portion of anatolia
during roman times
do you know what it is called
it was called
asia
so these were the various anatolian
provinces during roman times this these
were the administrative divisions
of anatolia and surrounding regions
during the roman era you had asia you
had galatia
bethennia trace macedonia cappadocia
armenia
syria macedonia
arabia
cyprus lysia and so on so forth okay
so the
this province this region the western
part
of anatolia was called asia
and
where this name come from asia
there was a confederation of anatolian
principalities called asuva
during the hittite metana time
which is about 1500 bc
so this region was called asuwa at the
time the romans
distorted that into asia so asia was a
roman province
after the dissolution and
decay of the roman empire
the entirety of of everything west of
this place called asia began to be
called asia by europeans this is a
complete distortion of actual naming
names of the regions and this is a
eurocentric perspective they take
any random name and they assign it to a
place
like for instance we have
the what what do they call it
adam's bridge
which is rama
they have arbitrarily assigned a name
adam's bridge to the rama setu yes they
have arbitrarily called the kalinga
mahasagar the bay of bengal they have
arbitrarily called the sea of
sovereignty as the arabian sea
even the arabians used to call it the
indian ocean
the british and in the anglo-saxon
empire have arbitrarily changed the
names of
places all across the world
um sagar mata is now called mount
everest
yeah
and then the champa is now called the
south china sea i can give you thousands
of examples but let's not go there
so similarly this small province in
western anatolia was called asia
eventually the europeans gave the entire
continent west of this region the name
of asia
and now the americans have decided that
we will not use the term the indian
subcontinent to talk about the indian
continent a subcontinent instead we will
call it south asia so uh like manmath
points out whenever something uh
any achievement that is done by indians
they will termite a south asian
achievement great news for the people of
south asia and great news for south
asian origin people in the us but when
some bad news comes out of india they
will not use the term south asia they
will say it's something that's going
wrong in india
so any good thing that happens they want
to give the credit to this imaginary
place called south asia
and anything bad happens anything good
happens
anything bad happens they will blame
india for it for instance
in the uk you have various pakistani
origin criminal gangs
grooming gangs
that perpetrate all kinds of horrific
crimes
on on on
on girls
in the uk and the police doesn't ever do
anything about it so these gangs which
are all exclusively pakistani men
these gangs are in the media called
south asian gangs
yeah so essentially it it makes it look
because if you look at the so-called
southeast region it's mostly india
so
people readers who are not aware of
what's really happening will start
thinking of indians as criminals so
anytime something bad happens they will
blame it on south asia anytime something
good happens
so so it's it's like that so so they
when the
so this is the kind of playbook they are
using
any indian achievement is south asian
any bad thing also when it when it suits
them is south asian and so on
but typically the bad things don't come
out of india so if a bad thing is a
pakistani origin they will say that
south asian bad thing that sort of thing
so this is
something that is being orchestrated out
of the u.s it is something that comes
out of the american academia all
american academics and think tanks
exclusively use the term south asia to
talk about the indian subcontinent
so what do we do about this we should
stop using the term south asia lots of
indians
gullible indians they have been they
have started using the term south asia
we are south asians no you're not south
asians you're indians
even pakistanis are indians the entire
indian suburb continent is historically
cultural and ethnically indian
so please stop using the term south asia
start using the term the indian
subcontinent that will ensure that
that essentially tells you what is the
indian subcontinent
it is greater india
it is the future of khandabarat that's
what it is so please use the term indian
subcontinent do not use the term south
asia this is an insidious term
created by the americans
to
manipulate public opinion about india
and to steal credit from india when
required and to put blame on india when
it suits them
so that's the deal
okay rajesh kumar sharma says when will
india become the third largest economy
good question so currently the u.s
economy is the largest economy 25 or so
trillion dollars china comes next 19.9
almost 20 trillion dollars you know the
numbers may be here or there a little
bit but more or less accurate
the third largest economy is japan 4.9
trillion dollars then you have fourth
japan which is 4.2 4.3 trillion trillion
dollars
and then you have india at 3.53 which is
just ahead of the uk we have just
surpassed the uk and we are never going
behind behind the uk ever again right so
we are on an upward trajectory
we are the fastest growing major economy
in the world we are currently at three
point five three trillion dollars now
what do we mean by our gdp is three
point five three trillion dollars it
means that there is the gdp output
economic output of india per year
it's not the total value of india and
its economy it's the economic output per
year and that is growing it's growing
every year it's growing the first
quarter of this year it grew at 13.6
which is humongous let's see if we can
keep up the trade that would be great so
if we are currently at 3.53 and the
japanese economy is in the doldrums it's
not really expanding much it's currently
at 4.9 let's say five into three years
or five years so if the indian economy
from this starting point of three point
five three trillion dollars grows at
seven percent
per year
we will reach the five trillion dollar
mark by 2028
5.3
if we grow at eight percent we will
reach the five trillion dollar mark by
2027 88 we will be a 6.5 trillion dollar
economy by 2030.
you grow at 10
we will be at 5.2 trillion dollars by
2026 itself
and at that rate we will be at 7.6
trillion dollars by 2030
and if india grows at the incredible
rate of 12 per year
we will reach 4.96 almost 5 trillion by
2025 itself
and by 2030 we will be at 8.7 trillion
dollars at that rate so india is on the
right track
by 2030 no matter what happens we will
have crossed
five trillion dollars we would like to
reach there by 2025 actually for that
the indian economy will have to grow at
plus per year which is not out of the
realms of possibility
so things are looking good good for
india the only concern is that we need
to ensure that we don't get dragged into
any unnecessary conflicts right now we
need peace
we need
a 20-year period
of peace
no major geopolitical or military
contract if we can manage that
if you can engineer that sort of thing
we will be unstoppable we will be too
big for anybody for anyone to even think
of fighting
so at least until 2030 we need to ensure
that we are at peace with all our
neighbors no matter what is required
we'll do it and reach the
10 trillion dollar mark
and then it will be very hard for
anybody to even think
of trying to needle india or to
open any military conflict with india
that's where we are and that's where we
are going my dear friends
ronak says
what are your thoughts on mr on on mr
biden president u.s president biden
being given special convoy in the uk
for her great majesty the queen's
funeral while other lesser world leaders
will travel by bus
well
so uh mr biden
whenever he goes to uh
a nation outside the u.s he typically
prefers to travel by helicopter yeah not
even
limousine so
it's either a special helicopter
a u.s air force helicopter that's
specially used for the president
if not that then the special limousine
that has been designed for the u.s
president it's called the beast it's a
massive be you know beast-like limousine
very
very well
secured armored heavily armored well
protected and very comfortable
so he typically uses a helicopter or the
beast so when it comes to this funeral
of this uh individual the queen
elizabeth ii
many world leaders are going there for
the funeral
and mr biden is there he's going to be
there and he actually wanted to travel
by helicopter but
it was not deemed feasible that's why he
has been allowed to travel by that
special limousine which is called the
beast unfortunately the various other
world leaders who are going there will
have to travel together in a bus
mr biden said that i do not ever travel
by bus how can you expect me to travel
by bus i am the leader of the free world
yeah so uh
so why has he been given the special
permission
well because the us owns the uk
the u.s is the boss
whoever mr biden i mean
mr biden is the is is the
supposed the leader of the u.s so how
can they refuse him right
so
the uk is a vasal state when your
overlord
comes
to your territory you give him every
comfort he demands you you do everything
he tells you that's how it goes
with uh with the client with the with
the overlord in the wassail state that's
the relationship that's how it is
so that's why he has been given special
dispensation to do whatever he wants
maybe the journey is too short for to
for him to travel by helicopter and of
course we have to please we have to be a
little compassionate to mr biden he is
slightly advanced just a little bit
advanced in ages
so because of these factors and because
of his status as the
official representative of the overlord
that's why he has been given the this
this special
dispensation or permission to do as a
wishes on the soil of his
vasal the uk
right i'm sure that india the indian
prime minister is not going there we are
most likely sending uh
our president uh the lady what's her
name uh
mrs dropper the murmur yeah we are
sending her she is representing india in
the funeral and it's just a curtsy
it's not like we are giving any special
honors to the queen of england it's just
a diplomatic uh gesture
standard diplomatic gesture when a major
world leader good or bad dies you
typically pay a certain amount of
respect as a token gesture when that
other individual edwina mountbatten died
our incredibly magnificent and
magnanimous prime minister sri jawal
neruji he sent one or two indian naval
destroyers
to to the funeral to pay tribute to the
lady whom he greatly admired because she
was so magnificent like him yes so we
are not doing that anymore
we are just sending our president
to the funeral as a token gesture and
it's a good experience for the president
as well because i i think that could
probably be one of her first visits
outside india in her official capacity
as a president of india so it serves
multiple purposes and it is not some
great special uh
honor to
to the to the queen
okay dash plays says during the french
versus british conflict in india
do you think the french might have been
better for india or do you think that
all european conquerors have the same
mindset
what do you think peoples
my peoples what do you think
if instead of the british you had french
occupation and colonization of india do
you think india would be in a better
place today
do you think so i know we we would all
have been speaking french it is true but
apart from the french culture and
language do you think
india would have been better off india
would have been destroyed less india
would have had less famines india's
culture would have survived better do
you think so
let me
so let me tell you what i think of this
i'm sure you all know of this place
called purucheri
in southern india where is purucheri it
it used to be called pondicherry yeah
it's somewhere in southern india i've
been there actually very very nice place
very nice people
uh so it's actually
in the midst of
the tamil heartland
of india tamilnadu
it's a few uh maybe 150 or so kilometers
south of the great city of chennai
beautiful city of chennai that's
purucheri so this was ruled by the
french until
very recently into the 20th century
now in purucheri which was called
pondicherry there is something called
the immaculate conception
cathedral let's look at that
let us put that on the screen let me
google that
immaculate conception cathedral
pondicherry
this is the immaculate conception
cathedral pondicherry if you would like
to see what it looks like
here is what it looks like
this is the the building
yes now do you know the history of this
place
do you know the history of the
immaculate conception capita cathedral
in poetry it stands
on the location on the site
of the great veda puri ishwaran temple
which was demolished by the french east
india company in the 18th century i
think it was 14 um
1748.
what's the story behind this how do we
know this happened
because there was there is a diary that
was maintained by sri anandaranga pillai
who was appointed as the chief dubash by
the french in 1740 something
what is it dubash a translator who
speaks two languages the local language
which is tamil and the
foreign occupiers language which is
french
so sri anandaranga pillai spoke two
languages or maybe more but the two main
languages that are of interest are tamil
and french
so shri anandaranga pillai maintained a
diary in which he recorded all the major
events of his times
so um
there was this governor this french
french governor general of of this
region his name was joseph of francois
dupley
so he was the governor of pondicherry
when these events happened he had a wife
who was very strongly devout staunch
catholic and so on
so uh
the jesuits
the jesuit priests
were involved in this the jesuits are a
certain section of the
of the church
they are
they were the people who were typically
employed by the church to steal
knowledge from other places like from
the east essentially from mainly from
india scientific knowledge mathematical
knowledge astronomical knowledge uh
philosophical knowledge from india even
from tibet even from china and various
other parts of the world the jesuits
were involved in pondicherry
the jesuits obtained a letter a
permission from the king of france to
destroy the veda puri ishwaran temple
which was the principal temple that was
used that was that was the principal
temple of the people of putni cheri
yes the greatest temple in pondicherry
most of the people of manichari used to
go there
for
religious devotion and all that yeah
so the jesuits obtained permission from
the king of france to destroy this
temple but the people were against that
that's why they were not able to do that
because otherwise it would cause
disturbances and troubles
so uh what the jesuits started doing is
this they started
repeatedly desecrating the temple in a
variety of ways that's all mentioned in
the diary of shri another pillai
eventually
in 1748
at the peak of
english british french hostilities
pondicherry was besieged by the british
and most of the population
of pondicherry the hindus
they had moved out of town for
their safety
it is then
that the jesuits destroyed the temple
right
and this was done at the instigation of
the wife of shri dupley
the french governor general
so this is just a small sample of what
the french did in the small territory
that they ruled
imagine they imagine that they had ruled
the whole of india what do you think
they would have done
they could possibly have been possibly
not saying for sure
possibly could have even been
you know worse than the british who
knows it's a possibility
so my answer is my my
answer is very clear
all the european occupiers invaders
conquerors had the same mindset
they were all
principally motivated by a desire
to plunder the land and extract
everything of value out of it and
secondly
to spread their foreign religion into
india
so whether it's the british or the
french they essentially had the same
objectives
and the same overall
mindset
so there that's why i believe that
french rule over india had it happened
instead of british rule would have been
no different for india at the end of the
whole
process india would have been just as
destroyed as it was under the british
maybe even worse and culturally also the
same kind of damage would have happened
so that is what i think i have been able
to demonstrate to you from this one
example of the small territory of the
french rule and what they did there
so you can extrapolate that to the rest
of india had they been able to rule that
okay philippines philippines laksa says
how did the philippines become a
christian country do they know their
true history and why don't they
re-embrace their indigenous religion or
culture
so where are the philippines what is the
philippines it's it's a nation
let's go back to the map
where's the map we will put that on the
map and see where it is
uh
okay
i hope you all know where it is the
philippines in case you don't
this is india you know where india is
let's go east east east east of india
silent vietnam all that that is
southeast asia and then you have the
archipelago
which is now currently known for
whatever reason as the philippines
so this is the philippines and what is
their history how did they become
christian
philly the philippines are is an almost
exclusively exclusively and entirely
almost
christian nation catholic nation almost
entirely there are some pockets of of
indigenous
belief systems you know some
some tribes that are considered to be
primitive and backward and there are
some elements of some muslim people in
the philippines to some extent in some
places but overall it's christian it's
been for a very long time what is the
story
so if you go back a thousand or so years
maybe more philippines was hindu
yeah
because of the chola conquest and maybe
because of before that because of the uh
influence of the great kalinga
empire as well
so the kalingan the people of kalinga
have been trading with southeast asia
suvarnabhumi thailand cambodia vietnam
all that for more than 3000 years maybe
even before that yeah
so initially the whole of southeast asia
was indianized
by the people of kalinga the traders
and then you had indianized kingdoms
that sprang up in these regions
so that's how you had the first
indianization of this region you had the
establishment of dharma of
of various flavors of dharma whether it
is hinduism buddhism whatever you want
to call it and
of the sanskrit language then you had
the chola conquest which happened about
a thousand years before today it had
geopolitical reasons
so
the first uh the
so then you had something called the the
the raja of cebu cebu is this island
that you see here
yeah
so the uh first known raja or the maybe
the last known raja of cebu his name was
shiri lumai shri lumai he's believed to
have been half indian half malay
he was a chola prince maybe his mother
could have been of malaya origin maybe
his father most likely his mother yeah
so he was a minor priest of the uh minor
pre uh prince of the chola dynasty
half indian half malay and he was the
king of this island which is called cebu
in the philippines right
then you had a great
filipino freedom fighter his name was
sri lapu
shri lapu lapu who fought against
spanish colonization so there was this
portuguese
uh
portuguese pirate
portuguese imperialist called ferdinand
magellan who was trying to
circumnavigate the entire planet
so he was passing through the
philippines and he
he came up to his old the imperialist
colonialistic colonialist tricks
and the this guy
this great man shri lapu labu
fought against ferdinand magellan in a
battle that happened in the early in the
first half of the 16th century
the
imperialists were defeated ferdinand
maguirin was killed in this battle
and this delayed spanish colonization of
the region by about 40 50 years maybe 30
40 years yeah
so
sri lapu was also most likely a hindu if
not hindu then he was he
he was an animist or whatever the
filipino indigenous culture and faith or
maybe something syncretic
and then you had the period of spanish
colonization which which went on from
the night from the 15
from the second half of the 16th century
until 1898
the philippines this nation is named
after a spanish king king philip ii who
was in power in the 16th century yeah
so in the
in the
last decade of the 19th century in 1896
i believe there was a filipino
uh
revolution they call it revolution it
was a war of independence yeah it was an
anti-colonial war against the spanish
occupiers it was brutally crushed by the
spanish spaniards then there was a
philippine declaration of independence
in 1898
when when did this declaration of
independence happen it coincided with
this spanish-american war which these
pineapples eventually lost
but instead of
instead of
respecting and honoring the philippine
declaration of independence the
americans occupied the philippines and
colonized it
good fun and then you had all kinds of
brutal atrocities that the americans
perpetrated on the philippines
yeah
and you can read about it
i'm sure you can read about it if you
look where um
uh so that's the story so that's how the
philippines were brutally transformed
into a christian country a catholic
country by the spaniards
the entire occupation lasted the
significant amount of time yeah
and so that's what happened
and every single
whatever
existed of filipino culture was brutally
smashed out of the filipino people
even today the filipino people are very
they're with they're very nice people
very very
very cultured people
that comes from their original culture
they're not like the spaniards
you know the the attitude and the
cultural outlook of filipino people
is
markedly different from though that of
spanish people
so that difference comes from the old
culture whatever of that still remains
in the philippines but they have lost
all traces of the culture they have no
written records left there are some
sometimes you find some artifacts which
are written in sanskrit
yeah but they they can no longer read it
they no longer remember what their
original culture was like there is no
trace of hinduism or or or their
pre-hindu culture
left at all in the philippines even if
they want to rediscover it and reconnect
with it there is nothing that can do
about it so it's been thoroughly
uh destroyed filipino culture
and
i think uh the current president of the
philippines mr duterte
he had expressed a desire to rename the
nation to maharlik
which seems to have some kind of
sanskrit origin
i'm not sure if it will ever be done but
he had
said that he wanted to do that at some
point in time
so yeah that is the deal about the
philippines that's that's story that's
how it all happened it was their culture
was smashed out of them by the spaniards
the spanish have been also have also
been incredibly brutal wherever they're
ruled
um and the philippines are a good
example of that
okay
studious psycho says i read an article
in hindu sometimes where they were
comparing
mr atta turk with mr with the great
shrinerosi
uh and so on so forth kamal ataturk
built the golden way of turkey nero took
credit of various things
i don't think they had anything in
parallel do you think they had and so on
yeah thank you
so
is there any way we can compare
mustafa kemal atathirk with the
magnificent shri jawalal nehru ji
so let's let's
look at the careers of both people mr
nehru was born into a very affluent
family
yeah
very powerful family his father was was
a very affluent very prosperous person
i don't know the entire history of his
father his family but
there are various stories that are told
i'm not sure what to what extent what is
true but yeah
and he had a
privileged
upbringing
he was educated in england he had all
the
trappings of wealth and luxury and he
was selected as the prime minister of
india even though
whatever little democracy existed had
voted for mr patel
but mr gandhi
armed twisted the indian national
congress
into
agreeing to his demand
to appoint mr nehru as the first prime
minister of india after the transfer of
power from the british to the indian
national congress
so mr nehru did not have any genuine
struggle whenever he went to prison
under the british it was typically in a
five-star jail
yeah
it was not the kind of prison that you
would have in kalapana in the andamans
or anything like that his first
experience in prison was kind of
uncomfortable
and after that he ensured that he never
had to experience it again so all the
other times he was imprisoned was in
relative luxury now let's talk about mr
ataturk
mr atatork
he was born in the 19th century
in salonika
which is present-day thessaloniki in
greece
he had a tough childhood
i think his father died early
his mother was of i think albanian
ethnicity his father was a turk
and uh
he was good at math he was good at the
geometry all those things he went to
military school he found that he had a
great aptitude for all things military
he became a young officer
he was for some time involved in some
rebellion against the caliphate against
the sultan he was in prison briefly but
then he was
allowed to go back to military life
he was a soldier he participated in
various wars
uh eventually what he did was he fought
in he fought in the first world war he
defeated
the british and the allies at gallipoli
in this great debacle that happened in
the galapagos peninsula which was all
at the behest of winston churchill he
thought that he would be able to
you know capture constantinople istanbul
he failed only because of the exploits
of one man mustafa kemal
it was a terrible campaign but ataturk
came out of it with incredible
uh success in flying colours that
enhances its reputation incredibly in
turkey
at the end of world war one turkey was
destroyed turkey was defeated the allies
the victorious powers had partitioned
turkey into numerous pieces
ataturk
did not accept that
he went to war he fought the turkish war
of independence not only against the
europeans
against the european european occupying
powers but also against his own sultan
the last sultan of turkey the caliph
and against
all these forces ranged up against him
he was fighting a lone campaign
alone against everybody else and yet he
came out on top he succeeded and he
dragged turkey out of occupation and
partition
into independence he carved an
independent turkey out of nothing
you know turkey was done
but just because of the the strength of
will and the exploits of one man
turkey was able to be independent so he
fought the occupiers he fought the
sultan
and he grabbed independence and victory
with his own two hands and he brought
that to turkey
through sheer force of will and through
his military expo exploits can you
compare a man like that
with the great magnificent sri jawal
niruji can you i will leave the answer
up to you that's for you to judge
mother says can you tell me about the
origin of the sindhi people are they
aryan or dravidian
look there is no such thing as aryan or
dravidian these are
fake categories created by the foreign
occupiers of india these are fake
eurocentric categories there is no such
thing as aryan or dravidian the people
of india are one people
they have the same origins
yeah now when it comes to the sindhi
people well where is sindh let's let's
go to the map
where is the map so i am sure all
indians know where sindh is
sindh is this part of the indian
subcontinent or west of gujarat and
rajasthan
the capital used to be mean and nagar
that is now called karachi it was called
bina nagar during the reign of the great
maha chatham
so and there is this other city called
hyderabad in this region i'm not sure
what its original name was and sindh is
named after the sindhu the great river
sindhu which is
the westerner is called indus
so what's the origin of the sunday
people well this region has been under
human occupation for tens of thousands
of years the first time homo sapiens
came here was about 75 80 000 years
before today when the out of africa
migration happened through the bab
al-mandeb straight over here
and the arabian peninsula was all dry
and deserted but the coastal regions
were greenish that's why homo sapiens
was able to travel northwards then there
was a second crossing over here the
strait of hormuz
and that's where homo sapiens first
entered the region of the indian
subkanen if you consider iran and porsha
to be part of the indian subcontinent
which is it is geographically part of
and then because of because the coastal
regions were still kind of green and
forested homo sapiens went west
westwards and then reached india the
indian subcontinent which is full of
rivers incredibly rich fertile soil
excellent climate that's where the first
human inhabitation out of africa
happened
and since then the region of sindh and
the indian subcontinent have been
inhabited now if you look at the recent
history there used to be a kingdom
called sindhu and a kingdom called
savira
which are attested to in the mahabharat
i think the great warrior karna speaks
about the people of soviera of the
soviet kingdom and so on so the sindhu
soviet kingdom
has been here
i mean it inhabited this region
for i mean ever since the mahabharat
times
we don't quite know when the mahabharata
happened let's say
four or five thousand years before today
maybe five thousand day maybe six
thousand years somewhere around that
so this kingdom was there at that time
so the people of sindh are essentially
the people of india there is nothing
genetically specifically different about
the people of sindh or the people of
balochistan from the other people of
other parts of india
so that essentially in brief is the
origin of the sindhi people
um
you also had the great saraswati sindhu
phase of indian civilization which was
centered around the great rivers river
valleys the seven river valleys in this
region
including the two great rivers the
saraswati in the saraswati no longer
exists but it used to be in this region
and so on
so that is the origin of the sindhi
people which is the same as the origin
of the people of the indian subcontinent
and india
and pakistan afghanistan
nepal bangladesh
sri lanka maldives
and so on and so forth did i miss
something if i did apologies but yeah
you get the point
right
dr neeraj tweeted once
that early wheat evidence from bagash
central asia
uh share common morphological traits
with wheat from indus
during earlier phases of the third
millennium bc and this proves the
dispersal of the crop from bharat rather
than being carried across the eurasian
step
what's your
thoughts on this
and
another question about dr nirajara
finding a r1a sample from the scenario
site
let me take the second question first i
don't know for sure uh i'm not sure if
he has tweeted about this
uh if
the
a sample an r1a sample has indeed been
found it will eventually
be written about
the entire study will be published in a
scientific journal and then we will know
so i don't have any any special
information that others don't know i
haven't spoken to him about this
particular matter
maybe we will revisit this again we will
visit this perhaps in the next
conversation that i have that we have on
this channel but yeah thus far i am not
sure about whether it is true or not
now about wheat and all that we know
that the earliest evidence of
agriculture
attested to homo sapiens anywhere in the
world is in the indian subcontinent now
the eurocentric
uh
establishment historians have been for
the longest time claiming that
agriculture first emerged in the
so-called fertile crescent region what
is the fertile crescent region it is
this region uh you know the crescent
region
syria jordan israel
northern egypt
parts of anatolia that region so the
western historians and their indian
their indian 2ds have been saying this
for the longest time that agriculture
first emerged there well now lots of new
evidences emerged of agriculture having
emerged in india way way before this the
oldest
known evidence of agriculture in india
in the indians of continent is from 17
500 or so years before today from
sri lanka
and i say it's the indian subcontinent
because 17 000 years ago
there was the ice age in effect and
there was no
sea
between india and sri lanka india and
sri lanka were the same land mass sri
lanka was geographically and physically
part of the indian subcontinent at the
time
so the oldest evidence of agriculture is
from 17 point something years ago in sri
lanka and you have lots of other
evidence of of agriculture from the
ganga yamuna plain region in other parts
of india from twelve thousand eleven
thousand years ago ten thousand years
ago and all that
so what dr nirajara tweeted i i remember
seeing the nature paper it was published
in 2020. i don't have it right now i
cannot put it up i suppose you can all
take a look at that
and that nature paper is what dr
nirajara was referring to
let me see if i can actually pull that
up
that paper that was published in nature
and that is what dr neeraj i was
referring to
uh i may have it here let me put that on
the screen how nice i have it
here is the paper was it from 2020
it was published in 2018
early new neolithic agriculture and
cushion period developments macro
botanical evidence
from kanespur in kashmir india and this
is the paper that dr rai was most likely
referring to and all of these pieces of
evidence that we are now discovering
they demonstrate that agriculture
evolved emerged in india before
any such thing emerged in the so-called
fertile crescent agriculture in india
predates agriculture everywhere else so
this particular tweet that he must have
tweeted would have been part of that
that overall
uh
pattern of discoveries that we are now
making yes
so that's what it is
sound guy abhishek varu says you
you unclothed some mind shackling facts
about that japan
and germany are still under us military
control
occupation
do you have similar brain blowing facts
brain blowing facts
regarding israel maldives in italy
respectively
okay
it would be too much to unpack if i go
into all three nations so let's talk
about italy
let's talk about italy
i have demonstrated multiple times
that japan is under complete
u.s control and
massive american military occupation
there are more than 130 permanent u.s
military bases on japanese soil
i've also demonstrated that germany is
similarly under permanent u.s military
occupation what about italia
italy is a wonderful country isn't it so
what about italy is italy also under u.s
military occupation in somewhere in the
indirectives
italy also has numerous
military bases
that the u.s has been operating since
the end of world war ii
and if you know where to look you will
find lists
i'm not going to put it up right now
because i have not pulled up the list
and i will leave some of the
research and analysis for you you can do
a little bit of homework yes look it up
if you are if you are so inclined if you
are interested in this matter there are
a number of us permanent military bases
on italian soil now you know what the
portrait i think if you see
if you look up the wikipedia entry for
these individual military bases they
will say that these bases are jointly
operated by italy and the us and it's
completely under the italian control the
italians have can can take assumed full
control anytime they wish to that's what
i think wikipedia the wikipedia article
say but the fact is that all of these
military bases were established by the
us at the end of the second world war
and they have been operating this bases
ever since italy so italy is also just
like japan and germany under permanent
u.s occupation
yes now let's let's take a look at some
other interesting facts
shall we let's take a look at another
fact
uh
let me put this article on the screen
which will give you another dimension to
the whole issue what countries have
nuclear weapons and what where are they
so
as part of this
let's talk about u.s nuclear weapons
outside the us
about half
of the roughly 200 us shorter range
weapons are believed to be deployed in
five nato countries in europe belgium
germany
italy the netherlands and turkey
although the us does not confirm or deny
their specific locations yeah and so on
and so forth and this is all aimed at
encircling russia
yes
now do you see italy figure in this we
are not surprised to see germany germany
we know is under permanent u.s military
occupation yes the constitution of
germany was created by the americans
essentially indirectly it was all done
by the americans
italy also
has us nuclear weapons on its soil
tell me something
will a sovereign nation allow another
country
to operate military bases on its soil
and put nuclear weapons aimed at a third
country
it
doesn't make any sense so
there is a lack of sovereignty and the
loss of sovereignty have been disagree
so if you are interested please look up
which are the u.s military bases on
italian soil when were those military
bases
opened how long have the americans been
stationed on these military bases how
long have they been operating the bases
and then a whole interesting new picture
will unfold right in front of your eyes
not just japan not just germany italy is
also under permanent u.s military
occupation
right
somnath says as you have always said
aircraft carriers are sinkable
they are vulnerable
they are prone to attacks more attacks
than islands okay
instead of working instead instead of
using aircraft carriers working on
submarines would be a better solution my
question is how about carriers that can
submerge under the ocean
to avoid the enemy and are functional to
launch drones or land helicopters will
that design be a valuable ad for us
you know
the idea of
submersible aircraft carriers crops up
from time to time
yeah
and it's actually been done in the past
during world war ii the japanese
operated at least a couple of
submarine aircraft carriers
and they did not just have helicopters
they had those floating planes you know
planes that can land on sea and take off
from sea
they have
skis and stuff instead of wheels
uh sea planes they're called right
so each of
these submarine aircraft carriers
operate operated by the japanese
had the capacity to to hold at least two
of those planes
so that concept has been tried and
tested it actually works
at least one of these submarine aircraft
carriers was surrendered to the us at
the end of world war ii so it's been
done
now what about the 21st century
so typically when you talk about
aircraft carriers you're talking about
ships
that can launch fighter planes the
indian aircraft carriers have a capacity
of about 30 or so fighter planes the
american aircraft carriers have a
capacity of 80 plus
fighter aircraft maybe 80 plus maybe
even 90 plus yeah i don't remember the
exact number you can look it up if you
want
now when it comes to helicopters and
drones it's it's a significant climb
down of capacity capability the entire
point of an aircraft carrier is power
projection massive power projection
that's the whole point it's intimidation
more than actual warfare you send an
aircraft carrier near a nation it it if
that nation is not a superpower it's
gonna scare that nation it's gonna
intimidate that nation that's what the
americans and the british tried in 1971
when they sent one aircraft carrier each
into the bay of bengal
yeah
so that's the whole point
uh now
in warfare you want planes to be able to
take off and land take off and land do
multiple sorties from an aircraft
carrier
go drop your weapons load come back land
refuel then get out again with new
weapons
if your aircraft carrier is under the
water
your plane will not be able to
land multiple times and do multiple so
it is without exposing the location of
your submersible aircraft carrier so
that kind of defeats the purpose of a
submersible aircraft carrier so when it
comes to proper big
uh 100
uh you know the
90 plus aircraft aircraft carriers it's
hard to imagine or hard to conceptualize
making that sort of uh ship a
submersible or submarine ship yeah
when it comes to drones or helicopters
it can still be done i'm sure but
nobody's
taking that seriously or considering
that for a variety of reasons mainly
because once you once you
surface you are exposing your position
and then you are vulnerable to attack
so what is now
the focus is now on underwater drones
so you know autonomous submersible
vehicles autonomous submarine submarines
and maybe with that you may have some
kind of drone
aerial drone or something like that that
could be paired so i'm sure there are
multiple uh research and development
programs that are underway but as far as
i know
for the reasons that i just outlined
nobody is considering the the submarine
aircraft career very seriously even
though the
the
idea does crop up from time to time yeah
all right let's take some audience
questions somebody is saying no audience
questions all right let's take a few
audience questions
maybe two three
all right if you have any interesting
questions please ask me now
all right all right let's see uh if
there is any interesting
no audience questions go ahead ask me
questions go on
ah yes yes of course q had built a
submersible aircraft carrier in james
one movie
which movie was that was it a roger
moore movie
i kind of remember as a kid watching an
aircraft
watching a james bond movie
with submarines
and things like that there was a movie
in space as well moonraker
roger moore was there yeah
so that idea has always been around
isn't it
survey says is academic excellence
everything
no excellence is in life is everything
your academic
whatever you your academic performance
is not a real
is not a reliable indicator of your
performance as an adult after you're out
of your schooling and education system
there are people who do terribly in
academics who and who are brilliant
entrepreneurs let me give you an example
gary vaynerchuk
gary vaynerchuk i believe is dyslexic or
something he's not great at reading
and he did not
perform well at all in academics and yet
he has built i think a billion dollar
plus plus company or a group of
companies
and he is very active on social media
and all that he is he's a brilliant
enterprise very successful very
successful entrepreneur and he was not
academically excellent look at uh albert
einstein he did not do well in academics
but he's one of the greatest scientists
of all time
maybe the greatest scientist of the 20th
century look at srinivas
terrible and academics but one of the
greatest
greatest mathematical geniuses in the
past 1000 years yeah top three top five
so academic excellence is not everything
if you are not doing well academically
it doesn't mean you should be
disheartened it doesn't mean that you
will do poorly in life maybe you will do
better in life than most of your peers
who are getting first rank or whatever
it is right so that is how it is don't
i i personally don't place any
emphasis on what your academic
performance has been like your aptitude
your eagerness to learn
your your attitude towards life
and your
and and what really matters is that you
are always willing to learn something
new and to work hard
talent
versus hard work academic excellence
versus hard work hard work will always
trump all these factors all right
okay let's take maybe one more question
uh
what do we have
uh let me see if there is any
interesting other question
does turkey have more geopolitical
influence than india
uh
in the past i am sure turkey did have
more geopolitical influence because of
the leftover halo effect of the ottoman
empire which controlled massive parts of
europe in asia but also after world war
two
because it stayed neutral in world war
two it did not take sides and then it it
essentially became
a client state or a vasal state of the
us and that's why it became a member of
nato because of all these activities and
all these
geopolitical choices that it made
it
acquired a significant geopolitical
influence it was allowed to prosper by
the us it was allowed to capture
northern cyprus because it is currently
being being allowed to to
you know occupy parts of syria and so on
so because it is on the good side of
nato mostly and on the good side of the
us it has a certain amount of
geopolitical influence it has
mr erdogan has kalif like ambitions
again he wants to be the one he wants to
revive the ottoman empire essentially
and become the next sultan and so on
but turkey has
a limited size
yeah unless they go full conquest like
they like the past they will be able to
not go beyond a certain level
india on the other hand has unlimited
potential india overlooks the indian
ocean region the entire massive
piece of real estate global real estate
and india has a young vibrant incredibly
talented population
incredible resources this sky is the
limit for india so going forward india's
graph is rising i don't i don't know how
far turkey's graph will rise it is
closely related to the to the western
graph
if the us keeps declining the turks will
have to
make choices maybe align with china
maybe with russia they're trying to
allow they've been supporting pakistan
for the longest time and so on
so i think
as of 2022 india already most likely has
more geopolitical influence
and it is only going to keep rising
militarily india is still
you know not biting india's still biding
its time and not showing any real
capabilities which i think is a good
it's a good
strategy
good
okay one last question
who will get it
mass idiocracy says who cares about
turkey you have to care about every
single
player in geopolitics you may like them
you may dislike them that's a whole
different thing but if you underestimate
something somebody that may be the last
thing you will do
never underestimate anybody
right what else
i let me take one more then
shaheen says who was gaja mada gaja
mother was a
was a general and a prime minister of
the majapahit empire in indonesia
which was the golden period of you know
of indonesia's
history
um
and there's a whole story in history
associated with that that was the
pinnacle of indonesian history the
cultural uh
the cultural zenith of indonesia which
is when indonesia was a hindu empire
uh
and so on yeah so that's who gaja mother
was he was the greatest leader the
greatest general and prime minister of
the time he was not the king but he was
the most powerful man in the empire
gaja mother all right my dear friends
this is the end of today's episode
always always great fun talking to you
all always great to have all these
wonderful questions and we shall repeat
this process next week in episode
136 onwards going forward all right
until then take care
and i will see you very soon as always
take care bye